Yogesh Kumar

Jaipur, Rajasthan (India) Email: yoku2010@gmail.com | Mobile: +91-8130935784

Objective

I am seeking an opportunity to manage and lead large projects where my advance skills and education training and many years of experience can be fully utilised. And to obtain a position that promotes growth in which I can contribute my leadership skills and continue to develop experience in a professional community.

S yogesh_kumar1988

online resume

? yoku2010

in yoku2010

Skills

Proficient

- JavaScript
- Angular
- TypeScript
- Python
- ReactJS
- Redux

Comfortable

- Karma
- Jasmine
- Git
- MvSQL
- HTML5 & CSS3
- SASS/SCSS

Familiar

- jQuery
- MongoDB
- Redis
- D3.js
- Machine Learning
- Node.js

Professional Experience

02/2020 -Cont.

MEDdelivery (Liniment Pharma Private Limited) | Principal Engineer

Jaipur

- Planning, tracking, managing product releases and providing visibility to the operator (In-house Team) facing personnel/customers, as appropriate.
- Architectural design and provide solutions.
- Technical adviser and help team members by establishing processes/agendas, planning work & reviewing tasks.
- Code reviewer and Technical Interviewer.

08/2014 -01/2020.

Excelsoft Technologies Pvt. Ltd. | Lead Engineer

Noida

- Involved in both products and services development including solution designing, product development, and documentation.
- Mentoring and helping team members by establishing processes/agendas, planning work & reviewing tasks.
- Interacted with clients for requirement gathering, daily stand-ups and followed an Agile methodology.

11/2013 -06/2014

eTouch Systems Pvt. Ltd. | Software Engineer

Gurugram

- Developed a Training Project Management System for CISCO using Python, Django AngularJS and MySQL.
- Internal Product Release, create technical documents and coordinating daily with clients.

11/2012 -11/2013

HT Media Ltd. | Sr. Software Engineer

Gurugram

- Product development, bug fixes, performance improvement and documentation.
- Developed candidate module of shine.com using Python, Django, jQuery and MongoDB.

04/2010 -10/2012

Codescape Consultant Pvt. Ltd. | *Team Lead*

Jaipur

- Products and services development & documentation and provide client support ondemand.
- Developed web applications backend and frontend.
- Training delivery and technical presentations.

Projects

MEDDelivery | An ERP system to place orders for B2B pharma supply chain

MEDDelivery

- To organize & integrate commerce, logistics & data across in a single value chain.
- Technologies used: Angular, TypeScript, Python, Django and PostgreSQL.

PBS KIDS - Progress Tracker | Data Analytical and Storage System

pbskids.org

- To store, validate game & video events data and generate various reports.
- Research & development and made different POCs using Spark, Kibana, Logstash and Elasticsearch.
- Technologies used: Python, Django, MySQL, Cassandra, RabbitMQ, and jQuery.

PBS KIDS - Graviton | Event Data Analytics System

pbskids.org

- To store events in the database and compute various aggregate functions to generate stats for a game player.
- Technologies used: AWS Lambda Functions, DynamoDB, NodeJS, and TypeScript.

PBS KIDS - BosonJS | Data Computation System

pbskids.org

- Realtime calculation (algorithms) on game, video & activities data and provide stats.
- Technologies used: NodeJS, ExpressJS, Angular, TypeScript, RethinkDB, Redis, and RabbitMQ.

PBS KIDS - Fascia | System Monitoring Tool

pbskids.org

- Monitor & administration web applications and their components.
- Technologies used: NodeJS, ExpressJS, ReactJS, Redux, ECMAScript, D3, SASS/SCSS, and MongoDB.

Shine | Online Recruitment Portal

shine.com

- Job seeker can register, create their profile and apply for jobs.
- Recruiter can register and find best Candidates.
- Technologies used: Python, Django, jQuery, MySQL, and MongoDB.

Unified Network Management Platform | Configure, manage and monitor network devices

UNMP

- Robust & scalable platform for configuring and monitoring the IP-based devices present in any enterprise or carrier-grade network.
- Search the newly installed network elements, allow to manage, group the network devices/nodes based on their location and types.
- Integrate number of devices with UNMP easily and seamlessly.
- Technologies used: Python, Django, jQuery, MySQL, Nagios, RRDTool, SNMP, UPnP, and TCP.

Education

B.E./B.Tech | Information Technology

University of Rajasthan

• Govt. Engineering College, Ajmer (Rajasthan)